One Day, in a town at the edge of the world.
某一天，在世界尽头的一个小镇
The tide went out and never returned.
潮水退去不再回归
The sea just left without warning.
大海毫无征兆地消失
At first people were little more than puzzled.
起初人们只是困惑
They continued to gossip and fight over the same old things.
他们开始了无休无止的争论
But soon a silence began to permeate the township.
后来寂静蔓延
A desert of unbelievable magnitude was beginning to form before their very eyes.
荒芜的未知世界降临在人们眼前
We come together as family and friends
家人和朋友今日在此相聚
to farewell him and to grieve him.
为他送别，为他祭奠
we think especially of you, his family
尤其是你们，他的家人
Andrew, Penny, Jonathan.
Andrew, Penny, Jonathan.
For the loss of a father, a father-in-law and grandfather.
你们失去了一位父亲，一位公公，和一位祖父
Part of our grief may be regret for things done
我们的哀思包含着对过去
or left undone.
或者未尽之事的悔意
words said...
说过的话
...or words never said.
还有未曾说出口的那些
Yes?
你好
Is Andrew there?
Andrew在吗？
You must be Paul.
你一定是Paul
Please, come in.
请进
I'm Penny.
我是Penny
- Hi,Penny. - Andrew's wife.
- 你好,Penny - 我是Andrew的妻子
Ah, they're in here.
他们回来了
Andrew?
Andrew？
Sorry...
对不起
My plane was delayed in Hong Kong.
我的班机在香港延误了
Paul?
Paul？
Thanks.
谢谢
- Andrew? - Thanks.
- Andrew？ - 谢谢.
Jonathan.
Jonathan.
So, how's London? Is that where you're based?
伦敦怎么样？你现在住在那里吧？
Actually I'm spending more time in Istanbul these days.
其实近期我住在伊斯坦布尔的时间更多
Oh Jesus, fuck it, my balance is completely...fuck.
该死，我的平衡能力实在是...
It's fine, really.
没事的
You have a nice place. You've done well.
你家不错，看来你过得很好。
I'll get Penny to make up a bed in a spare room.
我会让Penny给你准备一间空房
- No that's fine. I made reservations from London. - No,really,it's no trouble.
- 不用了，我已经预订了旅馆 - 住下吧，不麻烦的
No it's done. Andrew it's done.Thank you.
不用了，Andrew，谢谢你
He's gone.
他走了
Yeah.
是啊
Paul, wait!
Paul, 等等
Paul, come back!
Paul, 回来
Paul, don't leave!
Paul, 别走
Paul!
Paul!
Andrew!
Andrew!
Shit!The lawyers.
该死，忘了去见律师
Oh fuck!Sorry.
该死，对不起
Sorry, I wanted to be there.
对不起，我打算去的
Slept in.How did it go?
睡过头了，情况怎么样？
He left you a third.
他留给你三分之一的财产
Well...you deserve two thirds.
那三分之二应该你拿
He left me a third as well.
我也只拿了三分之一
And the rest?
剩下的呢？
He left it to a charity.
他留给了慈善机构
Listen, I need to move on this,
听着，我赶时间
We need to clear the orchard and the cottage. I can't wait around, Paul.
我要去清理果园和小屋，那我先告辞了, Paul
I made an appointment for you to see the lawyer on Tuesday.
我约了律师周二见你
Well, I'll drop by and see him later.
好，我一会儿顺便就去
You can't just drop by and see
你不能就这样...
you can't just drop by and see them, Paul.
你不能就这样顺便去, Paul.
Right.
说得对
Hey you know what?
听我说
Another job came through.So
我又接到了工作
I'm leaving, tomorrow.
明天要走了
Well you obviously have more important things.
你当然有更重要的事
I'll see you in another 17 years.
我们就再过17年见吧
Come on Andrew, don't be such an old
Andrew, 别这样
Come on Andew, don't what?
别怎样？
How long have you been here, Paul? Two days?
你才来了几天, Paul？两天？
Forget the fact that this all just leaves me and
你没忘了当时你就是这样一走了之的吧
you're just like when mum died.
妈死的时候
Oh leave mum the fuck out of it, Andrew.
你他妈别提她, Andrew.
At least have the decency to do that.
对她尊重点
Decency?
尊重？
You think you're the one being decent?
你以为你比我强？
Swanning in here like some bloody film star with your accent?
带着一口英国腔站在这里趾高气昂
You know nothing about me, Andrew.
你什么都不知道, Andrew.
Listen, he would have wanted you to have these.
听着，拿着这个
I almost forgot.
差点忘了
They handed me this at the council meeting.
会议上他们给我的
You dropped it at the pub the afternoon of the service.
葬礼那天你忘在了酒吧
It could be useful getting home.
没有它你可能回不了家了
You didn't have to lie to me, Paul.
你没必要骗我, Paul
We weren't expecting you in the first place.
我们并没有希望你会出现
That's good wine you're spilling.
你洒的可是好酒
How did you find this place?
你怎么发现这个地方的
I heard music.
我听到音乐声
Mom doesn't know about this place?
妈妈不知道这里？
No, she doesn't.
她不知道
It's OK.
没事
You can stay.
你留下吧
One day in a town at the edge of the world.
世界尽头的某一天
The tide went out and never returned.
潮水退去不再回归
When do you think you'll learn?
你们什么时候能知道结果
As soon as we get these blood samples back and the swabs, a couple of days.
把血样拿回来之后，要过几天
I've extended my trip. I'll sort the house out.
我会多留几天，帮忙清理屋子
Paul
Paul
Thanks.
谢谢
Green tea.
喝点绿茶
What's he doing down there?
他在那儿干什么？
There's been an outbreak of some virus. I'm praying they're okay.
他们在处理屋子的细菌，但愿不会有什么问题
He cares about you, Paul.
他很关心你, Paul.
He never told Jonathan about me.
他都没有告诉Jonathan他还有个叔叔
We each have our own way of dealing with things.
我们都有处理问题的不同方式
I can't believe how much you look like mum.
你和我妈太像了
Who is she?
她是谁？
That's hope.
希望
Is she crying?
她在哭？
She's thinking.
思考
About what?
关于什么？
Many things.
很多
Turin Brakes "Full Of Stars"
Turin Brakes "Full Of Stars"
Jesus!
上帝
What are you doing here?
你在这里干什么？
It's just a place that I found that no one else comes to, I just...
我找到了这个没有人注意的地方，所以...
Did he let you come here?
他让你来的吗？
No.
不是
No one knows that I come here.
没有人知道我来这里
I should probably go.
我得走了
Yeah, I think you should.
你是该走了
I'll give you a couple of minutes to get your shit together and get out.
给你几分钟，赶快收拾东西走人
Paulie!
Paulie!
- Paulie Prior? - Hey, Winnie.
- Paulie Prior？ - 嗨, Winnie.
Look who it is
瞧瞧这是谁
How are you doing?
你还好吗？
I was looking for you at the service and I thought
葬礼那天我在找你
I bet the little bugger is here somewhere. And I dont' even recognize him.
我知道你会回来的，都认不出你了
Ah no I had some complications.
我遇到了一些情况
Oh that's a shame. Hey you remember Pat.
那可不太好，你记得Pat吧
Pat, look, look who it is. It's Paulie
Pat, 瞧瞧这是谁，是Paulie
Miss Seager!
Seager老师!
Hey, Paul.
嗨, Paul.
I had no idea you were still here.
我都不知道你还在这儿
What? you thought I'd dropped off the face of the earth?
你以为我从地球上消失了？
And he even has the fancy bloomin plummy accent.
听听他的一口英国腔
War zones.
战争
From the genocide in Ruwanda
从卢旺达的屠杀
to the ceaseless fighting in the Middle East
到中东的不断战争
and the horrors of the Bosnian conflict.
还有波斯尼亚冲突带来的恐慌
War zones have been both home and work
战争地区对你们将要见到的这个人来说
for the last decade to the man you are about to meet.
在过去十年成为了家园和工作地
A man whose dedication and courage
他的勇气和敬业
has gained him an international reputation of the highest merit.
为他赢得了崇高的国际荣誉
Not to mention
更不用说
the numerous awards he has received for both his articles and photographs,
它的报导和摄影作品获奖无数
and that he is an old dear student of mine
他曾经是我的学生
who I taught in these very buildings.
和你们一样在这里上过课
I present to you Paul Prior.
由请Paul Prior
Thank you.
谢谢
That was a very generous introduction, Miss Seagar.
刚才的介绍实在不敢当, Seagar老师
Yeah, my school reports were never that good.
我学生时的成绩可不怎么样
The truth is that
事实上
I've been called many things,
有很多人对我恶言相向
many worse things since I last stepped foot in this building
离开这里之后遭受过太多非议甚至辱骂
vulture, parasite ,leech
贪得无厌，寄生虫，吸血鬼
And it's amazing how insults in most languages sound pretty much the same.
不过我发现不同语言的侮辱，听来是相似的
I was once
我曾经
held captive for three days and publicly urinated on.
被囚禁三天，并当众侮辱
I don't really know what to say,
我不知道该说什么
but I'd be happy to answer any questions that you might have.
但是很高兴回答你们的问题
He was a finalist for the Pulitzer
他曾经获得普利策奖的提名
Pulitzer? What the hell is that?
普利策？什么鬼东西？
It's a huge prize.
是一个大奖
He had a one in three chance of winning it as well.
他当时有三分之一的机会胜出
How do you know this shit?
你怎么知道这些东西的
I read an interview.
我读过一篇访问
Sounds like a lone wolf.
听着像个独行侠
That reminds me, I'm thinking of getting a tattoo.
对了，我想刺个纹身
A little unicorn, right here.
在这里纹个独角兽
Why?
为什么？
Steve has exactly the same one?
Steve也有一个？
No I just think it would be cool.
我只是觉得会很酷
So anyway.
那么
How'd it go with Jake?
你和Jake怎么样了？
Piss off.
走开！
Tell me!
告诉我
first of all we had a moonlight stroll down the beach
我们在洒满月光的海边漫步
and a candle light dinner
享用了烛光晚餐
and then he told me what beautiful eyes I had.
然后他说我的眼睛很漂亮
Really?
真的？
No, you dyke.
当然不是
He only got drinks to go on the Big Day Out.
他只知道喝酒
You know he was like
你知道他那样子
Yo man. Yo bitch.
"嘿，老兄！嘿，小妞！”
And I think it should be quite so obvious.
他就是这样
I was reading the local rag today.
我刚看了这里的报纸
Front page.
还是头版
Oh God.
天哪
I'd forgotten how quiet is, really.
我已经忘了这是个小地方了
I've had this bloody ringing in my ears ever since I got here.
来了这里，我一直有该死的耳鸣
Maybe the change here will do you good.
也许你应该改变一下
Like I said, if you ever get bored photographing war.
如果你对做战地记者已经感到厌倦
You weren't being serious, were you?
你不是说真的吧？
I'm three staff down, Paul.
我手下有三个教员辞职了, Paul.
I know it might sound desperate, but
我知道这你不太能接受，但...
Pat, I'd be hopeless, I've never taught in my life. Come on.
Pat, 我不知道该怎么做，我可从没教过书
You went out and made something of yourself. What can beat that?
你可以用你的方式，那没问题吧？
Half these kids don't even know what's on the other side of those hills.
这里一半的孩子都不了解外面的世界
Paul!
Paul!
Paul gave Jonathan this.
Paul给Jonathan的
It's got a good zoom lens.
这相机变焦很好
It's much, much too kind.
这太贵重了
No, it's fine.
没事的
Honestly, I'm using digital these days.
我现在都用数码的
If you're going to be a serious photographer, you need a good zoom lens.
如果想成为好的摄影师，就要有好的相机
See you tomorrow then.
明天见
Goodnight. Paul.
晚安，Paul
Goodnight.
晚安
Jonathan said he gave a talk at the school.
Jonathan说他在学校作了演讲
Apparently the kids really liked him.
孩子们都喜欢他
Good.
这很好
Can I fuck you now?
我可以做你了吗？
God! You've got a way with words!
天哪，你用词太不注意了
Sorry, what do you want to do then?
对不起，那你想做什么？
What you all doing man?
你在干嘛
Just playing.
玩玩
Just play carefully.
小心点
Shit! Fuck you!
该死！去你的！
You were meant to stay still.
你不该动的
You look well.
你气色不错
Well, used more like it.
不如过去了
It's different.
你变了
You have an accent. So English.
一口英国腔
You think?
你这么觉得？
Well, it was inevitable.
这也是难免的
Sick of being called an Australian.
厌倦了被人叫做澳大利亚人
Fair enough.
好吧
Help yourself.
来一根吧
Oh no, I quit.
我戒了
Kids?
有孩子吗？
Two.
两个
One of each.
一男一女
Remember Ben?
记得Ben吗？
Ben Steimer.
Ben Steimer
Yeah.
对
We got together about 18 months after you left.
你走后一年半我们在一起了
He died when Elvis was five.
女儿五岁的时候他死了
Motobike.
摩托车祸
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I was pregnant with Sam at the time.
那时我怀着Sam
So I had the kids to think about and decided to keep the business running.
为了孩子，我决定开始工作
What was that?
你做什么？
Butchery.
肉店
Shortest butcher in New Zealand.
我是新西兰个子最小的屠夫
Really?
真的？
Yeah well, I'm a ninja with a boning knife .
我是持剔骨刀的武士
No surprises there.
我不感到惊讶
I see your brother from time to time.
我经常看见你弟弟
Yeah, he's up to his neck in ostriches.
对，他一直很忙
Is he still married? I never see his wife.
他没离婚吧？我没见过他妻子
No, yeah, I don't think she goes out much
没有，她只是不常出门
How many times have I told you about leaving the gate to the pen open?
我警告过你多少次了
If you think you're going to see this again you're mistaken.
如果你以为我会还给你，那就错了
You disgust me.
你让我恶心
Who the hell is this guy?
你要去见谁
Just an old school friend. It's no big deal.
一个老朋友，没什么
No big deal?
没什么？
Where's my jacket?
我的外套呢？
Celia, It's rubbish night.
Celia, 别忘了垃圾
And please tie the bags. I don't want dogs getting into them. Bye, bye.
把袋子系上，别让狗跑进去，再见
Hey, we'll be waiting.
我们等着你
Need a hand with that?
要帮忙吗？
Done your homework?
作业完成了？
Will you please take your foot away?
请把脚拿开
What? Just to see if you've done your homework.
我可是关心你
Just asking.
问问而已
I'm sure we used to be able to do this.
我们以前也这样做过
Did you think of me?
你会想到我吗？
I was terrified of seeing you.
我怕见到你
You remember those poems and stories you used to write?
记得你以前写的那些诗和故事吗？
I was going to put music to them, release an album.
那时我想写成歌，我们会出一张唱片
What were we were going to call ourselves?
我们的乐队叫什么名字来着？
What was it? Was it "silly bastards"?
是"silly bastards"吗？
"Stupid Buggers"
"Stupid Buggers"
"Sick Motherfuckers", "Sick Fuckers", wasn't it?
"Sick Motherfuckers", "Sick Fuckers", 是吗？
"Sick Puppy", actually.
是"Sick Puppy"
Live at the Hammersmith.
还有演唱会
Yeah, see that's me. Eight years behind what was going on. But, you know,
没有如愿以偿，回过头来看看曾经的自己
still thinking I had created it all for myself.
现在还是会白日做梦
Hi.
嗨
I've got an assignment where I have to interview an important local community member.
我在采访本地的名人
And it was a choice between you and Mr Aiken who set up the irrigation main.
我在你和造灌溉渠的Aiken先生之间选择了你
I was just wondering if I could interview you?
你愿意接受采访吗？
Can I come in?
我可以进屋吗？
Is there real coffee?
有真咖啡吗？
Sure. How do you have it?
当然，要喝哪种
Macchito, thanks.
Macchito, 谢谢
I'm Celia by the way.
我叫Celia
I gather you do have some questions.
你有问题要问吧？
Ah Yes. Ah Yeah.
嗯，对
So, how did you get to do what you do?
你怎样走上现在这条路的
I was working for a paper in London on local articles,
我在伦敦一家报社工作
and they needed somebody to go to Bosnia.
他们需要人手去波斯尼亚
That right, yeah. You were working as a typesetter in Wellington,
我知道，你在惠灵顿做过排字工人
and you studied journalism in London,
去伦敦学新闻
and found your break as a feature article writer,
后来成为专栏作家
and then a field journalist for Reuters.
又称为路透社的战地记者
And for the past three and a half years you've been solidly freelance living
过去的三年半你在往返于
between London, Istanbul and Paris.
伦敦、伊斯坦布尔、巴黎
Well done. Yes. That's it.
说得不错
You've really done your homework.
看来你下了点功夫
People must worry about you a lot doing this kind of work.
人们一定为你做这样的工作感到担心
Your wife? Children?
你的妻子？孩子？
No, not married.
我未婚
Single? Yes.
单身？是
What's it like going to war? Just to watch?
目睹战争的感受是怎样的
I'm not there to watch. I'm there to record.
我不是去目睹，而是去记录
Is that how you got those scars?
你的伤疤是因为战争留下的？
I fell off my bike when I was 12 coming down a gravel track.
12岁时骑车摔的
No other scars?
没有别的伤疤？
Are you going to drink your macchito?
你还喝不喝你的macchito？
What's the hardest thing you have to deal with?
你经历过最困难的情况是？
Jesus. Are these going to get any easier?
上帝，你的问题真难回答
I don't know, finding a loo when you need one,which always seems to be pretty fucking impossible.
不知道，在那儿找厕所倒是相当困难
Why don't you celebrate your birthday on Christmas?
为什么你不在圣诞节那天过生日？
Now tell me, which article did you read that one in?
这你又是在哪里看到的
It was your birthday when you took that photo of that girl.
你拍那女孩照片的那天是你的生日
The one you won the Pulitzer for.
那张作品获得了普利策奖
I was shortlisted.
提名
I read that when you got nominated
我听说你被提名后
you withdrew the entry.
自动退出
Long story.
说来话长
I've got a 120 minute tape.
我的录音带有120分钟
I was in Grozny
我当时在Grozny
I heard about an offensive that was being mounted against the Russians.
听说俄国佬将要遭到一次攻击
I was warned by some friends not to write about it
朋友们警告我不要写这篇报道
in case the Russians caught whiff about what was going to happen.
以防俄国人得知并发起反击
So what did you do?
你怎么做的
Wrote the article.
我还是写了
Then I declined sending it through to Reuters.
发给路透社
They found out anyway.
他们还是发现了
And they retaliated by massacring over 100 civilians in the village outside the city.
为了报复，在城外的一个村庄残杀了100多个平民
.And I'd been out all night drinking with people who were killed a few hours later.
那晚我喝了一夜酒 其中几个朋友几小时后也被杀害了
The girl in the photo was the
照片中的女孩
was the only survivor.
是唯一的幸存者
Did you know her?
你认识她吗？
No.
不
Was there anyone else around?
当时有别人在场吗？
Not at the time, no.
没有别人
Just you?
只有你？
Just me.
只有我
So then what?
后来呢？
I think your batteries are running flat.
我想你快没电了
Are you...
你是
Are you Ben Steimer's daughter?
你是Ben Steimer的女儿？
Did you know him?
你知道他
Yeah, we went to school together.
我们是同学
It's a photo of a baby.
一张孩子的照片
Whose?
谁的
I don't know. Do I need to?
不知道，我需要吗？
Yeah, look at the bracelet.
看看那条手链
No, look! "Celia, 27/2/87".
看着 "Celia, 27/2/87".
That's roughly 8 months after I left.
那是我走后的八个月
I sent that photo nearly 16 years ago.
我16年前就寄出这张照片了
Why did you send it?
为什么？
Why did you send it, Jax?
为什么寄, Jax？
You want an explanation?
你想听我的解释？
Do you know what's it like to be invisible, Paul?
你知道你彻底消失了吗, Paul？
Even just a postcard.
一张明信片
A phone call.
一个电话都没有
Hi Sid, up there next to the porkers.
Sid, 把它放那儿
Patti Smith "Free Money"
Patti Smith "Free Money"
It's in the past. OK?
都过去了，好吗？
Just leave it.
别管它
Will you be needing a copy of that?
你需要复件吗？
No, thank you.
不，谢谢
Oh my god. I think I need rescuing from these TV blokes.
上帝，我想我该从那群电视鬼中解脱一下
Is it a good book, is it?
是本好书吧？
"The Cloud of Unknowing", Sounds mysterious.
"未知之云", 好神秘
Where are you from?
你从哪儿来
Where am I from?
我从哪儿来
A long way from here.
很远的地方
Me too. Mind if I join you?
我也是，不介意我坐这儿吧？
Want a drink?
喝一杯？
I'd love one.
好
Kiss me.
吻我
Am I warm?
是这本吗？
Getting closer.
近了
Warmer?
这本？
Getting warmer.
差不多了
Warmer, in springtime.
就快了
Here!
这本!
Alone we are born
我们孤独地来到这个世界
And die alone
孤独地死去
Yet see the red-gold cirrus Over snow mountain shine
看那雪山之上的红色微光
Upon the upland road
在山路上前行
Ride easy, stranger
陌生的你请放慢脚步
Surrender to the sky, your heart of anger
仰拜天空吧，愤怒的心
Don't be frightened of possibilities, son.
不要畏惧无限的可能性，儿子
She's a wonderful mistress.
她是伟大的象征
It's ok.
没事的
Go back to sleep.
睡吧
I'm helping out for a couple of weeks.
我只是在这里帮一阵子忙
And I'm new at this, so be patient with me.
我没做过老师，请大家见谅
Who knows how many words there are in the English language?
谁知道英语中有多少词语
10 thousand.
一万
Dictionary. There's actually over 750,000 words.
字典上有超过75万
And I was a -- I thought maybe you could all choose a word.
我想让你们每个人选一个词语
Any word, doesn't matter what. Preferably something that means something to you.
无论哪个词，最好是对你们来说有一定意义的
And compose something on this word.
关于这个词写一些东西
Anything. It could be just a static image of you if you think that's easier.
无论什么都可以，可以是关于你们自己
Just so I get an idea of who you all are.
这样我可以认识你们
And what the F--- I've gotten myself into.
也看看现在自己处于什么情况
Hope.
希望
Her mind is a graveyard. Her heart is an island.
她的思想是一座坟墓，她的心灵是一座岛屿
She and I are not good friends but I've known her all my life.
我们并非深交，但却相识一生
She sits in my belly hollow and distant.
她离我如此近，却又那么远
And her whispered words of encouragement will never comfort me.
她的耳语从未抚慰我的心灵
Mom?
妈妈？
I'm on to her tricks. Her false promises.
我中了她的毒，她虚伪的承诺
"Go away", I tell her. "I'm busy today."" I've got things to do."
"走开", 我说，"我今天很忙"" 有事要做"
This acquaintance never knows when to leave.
她永远不会离开
It's not a question of why she befriended me in the first place.
问题不是她为何成为了我的朋友
It's more a question of why I choose to let her stay.
而是我为何没有拒绝
Tea bag! Tea bag!
茶袋!茶袋!
Tea bag!
茶袋!
- Tea bag! - Leave her alone, you fucking animal!
- 茶袋! - 放开她，你们这群畜牲!
Tea bag! Tea bag!
茶袋!茶袋!
Your knee's bleeding.
你的膝盖破了
I know. I fell.
我知道，我摔了一跤
Come on. Let's take a look at it, then.
我来帮你看看
Weeks passed
几周的时间过去
and there was still no sign of the ocean.
依然没有大海的痕迹
The people grew worried.
人们更加担心
It was decided to send a small group to search for it
他们决定派人去寻找
in the hope of bringing it back.
满心希望把它找回来
All right attention please.
大家请注意
I would appreciate it if everyone listened.
请听好
That includes you, Mr Brook.
包括你在内，Brook
Look. Have any of you seen Celia since yesterday?
昨天以后你们见过Celia吗？
No? Well, if she gets in touch with any of you,
没有？如果你们见到她
you know where to find me, okay?
告诉我好吗？
Thanks.
谢谢
All right. Settle down. We've all seen a police officer before.
大家安静，都不是没见过警察
Paul? Look, Just wondering. Can I have a word for a second?
Paul，能和你聊两句吗？
I'm already late for a class.
我上课要迟到了
It won't take long.
不会太长的
Back to class.
回去上课
Paul?
Paul？
Hey, Pat, It's fine. I'm just helping out with something.
Pat, 没事的，我只是在帮点忙
Thanks, Pat.
谢谢, Pat.
Hey, did you see Celia on the weekend?
周末你见过Celia吗？
No.
没有
She used to visit though, right.
她来过你家吧？
Yeah.
对
She came by sometimes to borrow books.
她会来借书
How often did she pop by?
她多久来一次
She liked to drop by most Sundays I guess, yeah.
大多是周日吧
Liked? Likes.
- Liked？ - Likes.
I said likes, I think.
我用的是现在时
Ah see cause I think I know what Celia likes.
我想我知道Celia喜欢什么
I mean I've known her since she was a little kid. She's my daughter's best friend.
她小的时候我就认识她了，她是我女儿最好的朋友
I also know that you sent her an e-mail on the weekend asking her to come by and visit.
我也知道你发邮件给她，让她周末去找你
She wasn't too happy about that from what I understand.
我了解到，那时她不太高兴
You see I know this, Paul
我知道这事儿, Paul
because Miso agreed to drop her off.
因为Miso答应她把她送到你家
Actually she did drop by briefly.
她是去过我那儿
It's nice out there at the orchard.
你那果园不错
Quiet. Private.
安静，无人打扰
So why did you stay on?
你为什么留下来？
Favour for a friend.
帮一个朋友的忙
How long did you guys go out for?
你们恋爱了多久？
What?
什么？
om
你和妈妈
Oh, she mentioned me.
她提到我了
When did you break up?
你们什么时候分手的？
God, seventeen.
十七岁
Listen, what you wrote the other day, I thought it was
那天你写的东西，我觉得
well considered.
考虑周到
Well considered. Intriguing.
- 考虑周到 - 引人入胜
I like what you've done here.
我喜欢你布置的书房
Where did all these books come from?
这些书是哪儿来的
He never told me.
他从没告诉我
Wanted to keep it a mystery, I suppose.
我想是保持神秘吧
Father's have got a lot to answer for, huh?
父亲总是那样的，不是吗？
Hey beautiful.
嘿，美人
Sorry I'm late.
对不起迟到了
She can't have gone far.
她不会走远的
Me and some mates are going to take a look around Lawrence later.
我和几个朋友一会儿要去Lawrence那儿
Can you bring those?
你能端那两个吗？
Sure.
当然
I asked for an essay about the pros and cons of immigration, Jake
我要你写的是有关移民的文章, Jake
not the best places to surf.
不是冲浪的好去处
Louise, Tonga has a king, not a president.
Louise, Tonga的元首是国王，不是总统
I think you'll find there's more to life in Hong Kong than dance clubs, Miso.
我想香港除了舞厅外还有更多值得关注的地方, Miso.
What? Like secret book clubs?
比如说？秘密书会？
Paul!
Paul!
Sergeant O'Neil's back.
O'Neil警官又来了
He's waiting for you in the common room.
他还在上次的房间等你
I told him you were busy.
我告诉他你很忙
You had nice handwriting as a kid.
你小时候写的字不错
Is this one of the books she borrowed?
这是她借的书吗？
I didn't
我没有
I didn't keep a record, to tell you the truth. I didn't.
我没有留下记录
What? Other things on your mind, did you?
什么？你想着别的事吧
We found this on the side of the road, bet it came from your place.
我们在路边发现的，我想是你的东西
Just want to know how it got there, that's all.
我只是想知道它是怎么到那儿的
Did she ever talk to you about leaving?
她跟你提起过要出走吗？
Name a teenager around here who doesn't.
这里的年轻人都想离开
I know a few actually.
那可不一定
OK. You can open your eyes.
睁开眼睛
Happy Birthday.
生日快乐
Who is this anyway?
这是谁的歌
Kiri Te Kanawa. You chose it.
Kiri Te Kanawa，你选的
Who's she?
她是谁
There are people in this country who would shoot you for asking that question.
你连她都不知道，很该死
There are people in this country who would shoot you for listening to it.
你听她的歌，才该死
So what's she singing about?
她在唱什么？
Love.
爱情
What do you normally do on a Saturday night?
周六晚上你一般干些什么？
Who do you hang out with when you're not having picnics with me?
不和我野餐的话，你会和谁一起
What do you do, go to parties or what?
你会做什么，参加聚会还是？
If you can call them that.
如果你称其为聚会的话
Why? Do you wanna come along? You actually might get to see them tea bagging.
问这个干嘛？你想加入？你可能会看到他们玩茶袋
Tea bagging? What's that?
茶袋？那是什么？
Well, That's when guys get a girl completely comatose
那个，是一群男孩把女孩灌醉
and then they take turns in lowering their testicles into her eye sockets and film it.
他们把那个伸进她的眼窝，然后拍下来
And if they're really kind they send a copy to a paranoid friend.
如果他们觉得有意思 会把照片寄给一个疯狂的朋友
First class is seminal? It's not funny.
射了的最好，我不觉得那很有趣
I don't know what we're talking about.
我不知道我们在说什么
Oh god.
上帝
Well I hope you keep your distance from those kind of guys is what I'm saying.
我希望你离那些男孩远些
So, tell me about you and mum, back in the dark ages.
说说你和我妈吧，回到黑暗时代
It wasn't that long ago.
没有你说的那么夸张
Patti Smith "Horses"
Patti Smith "Horses"
My mom wanted to sing like this?
我妈那时想这样唱歌？
Your mother wanted to be Patti Smith.
你妈想成为Patti Smith
Come with me. Come on.
跟我来，快
I'll show you something.
给你个惊喜
Where did this place come from?
这是什么地方？
No one knows about it except me and my dad.
只有我和我爸知道
So what are you doing here?
你们在这里干什么？
Write.
写作
Think.
思考
Mystery boy.
神秘男孩
So many secrets.
如此神秘
What are you doing?
你在干嘛
Giving you something to write about, moron.
给你找些素材，呆子
Mom the rock star.
摇滚妈妈
It's hard to believe she even had a dream.
不敢相信她也有过梦想
Do you want to know what my dream is?
你想知道我的梦想是什么吗？
Yeah.
想啊
I'm sitting in a cafe in Spain.
我坐在西班牙的一间咖啡馆
And don't know a single person there. And I can't understand a single word that anyone's saying.
不认识一个人，不懂一句话
I've got a glass of wine
我握着一杯酒
and I can see the sea.
看见海
Don't worry.
算了，还是不说了
No, go on. And?
继续啊，然后？
I'm just writing.
我只是写作
And yeah.
然后
And you know it doesn't matter if no one ever reads what I'm writing
我不介意有没有人看我的作品
I don't want to be famous.
我不想成名
I just, I just want to be there.
我只是，只是想在那儿
Anyway, I'd rather be a no one somewhere than someone nowhere.
宁可寂寂无名，也不愿迷失所在
I've already packed my suitcase.
我已经整理好了行李
I'm not joking.
我没有开玩笑
I'm not laughing at you.
我没有嘲笑你
I had a similar dream once.
我也有过这样的梦
Really?
真的吗？
Tell me.
告诉我
Sometimes I'd see...faces.
有时我能看见...人们的脸
At night before I fell asleep, people I never met.
入睡之前，陌生的人
And I'd wonder who they were.
我不知道他们是谁
Where they might live, what they did.
他们身在何处，他们所事何物
and it was strange
奇怪的是
because it was like they knew I was thinking about them.
好像他们知道我在想着他们
Why did you become a war journalist?
你为什么要做战地记者？
Who you set out to be is not always who you become.
你往往无法成为向往的自己
You know, Things happen. Plans change.
事情发生了，计划改变了
I see them too.
我也会看见他们
Faces.
人脸
I wanted to give you something.
我想给你个东西
I just, I think you should enter.
我想你应该参加
You never talk about your mum.
你从来没有说起过你的母亲
My mum? She's very religious.
我的母亲？她是虔诚的教徒
She had these little sermons about the beauty God hides away in quiet corners.
她告诉我上帝在安静的角落藏了美好
Is that what your dad was hiding from in here?
你爸爸在这里就是为了躲避这些吧
No, they
不，他们
I think she was just quiet, you know.
她只是很安静
My dad and her were very different.
我父母很不同
My dad didn't believe in anything. He's an atheist.
我爸不相信任何事，他是无神论者
My brother and her were very close.
我弟弟和她很亲近
I heard she had an accident .
我听说她发生了意外
Yeah she did.
是的
She was diagnosed as bi-polar, manic depression.
她被诊断得了抑郁症
Doctors prescribed lithium but she stopped taking it, I think.
她没有服医生给的药
What happened?
发生了什么？
She was standing in the river
她站在河里
at the back of the property and she pointed up to this hawk in the sky.
在农场的后边，她的手指向了空中的鹰
And then when I looked back she was gone.
我再次望向她时。她已经不在了
Found the body two days later, I think
两天后找到了尸体
Is that why you push people away?
这是你疏远人事的原因吗？
I do as I fucking please Celia. You know I hate to spoil your illusions.
我想做什么就做什么，Celia. 我讨厌打碎你的幻想
But the world out there isn't a bed of roses waiting to be picked
但是外面的世界不是等待采摘的玫瑰
or whatever it was you said, a glass of chardonnay in a fucking tapas bar.
或者像你说的，一个酒吧里的一杯好酒
You understand?
你懂吗？
It wasn't an insult.
我没有想过要冒犯你
Sorry.
对不起
OK.
没事
Hey, Jax.
嘿, Jax.
Hi
嗨
I saw the smoke and I didn't want to disturb you
我看到你这儿有烟，其实不想打扰你
but I remembered it was your birthday and so I
但是今天是你的生日，所以
Get in the car
到车里去
No.
不
Celia, I'm sick of this.
Celia, 我受够了
I said get in the car. I said get in the car
我说到车里去，到车里去
You have no right to be here. Night, Paul.
你没有权利来这里赶我走，晚安，Paul
You have the audacity to bring here and give her alcohol?
你把她带来这里，还给她酒？
Jax, it's not what you think.
Jax, 不是你想的那样
You even presume to know what I think?
你以为你连我怎么想的都知道？
Shit!
该死
Excuse me.
对不起
I need a notebook. I know it's here somewhere.
我要找一本笔记，应该在这里
Sorry, dad.
对不起，爸爸
There's nothing to be sorry for
不用道歉
as long as you're being cautious.
只要你们注意着点就好
Yeah of course.
当然
I'll be on my way.
那我走了
You shouldn't be here.
你不该来这儿的
He doesn't care.
他不在乎的
I mean you saw for yourself.
你也看到了
I care.
我在乎
What are you telling me?
你什么意思？
That I'm not as important as what goes on in your head?
你是说我不如你的想法重要？
There's just parts of me you can't have.
我的一部分是你无法拥有的
No one can.
没有人可以
Hey. You ok?
嘿，你好吗？
I'd rather look at it at your place.
现在别给我这个
What's this?
这是什么？
Jesus Christ.
上帝
Did she do this?
她打的吗？
Celia tell me, who did it?
Celia，告诉我，谁打的
I don't want to talk about it. It wasn't mom.
我不想说，不是我妈
Hey where is he?
嘿，他在哪儿
Paul, what are you doing?
Paul, 你干嘛
Paul, what are you doing in my house?
Paul, 你在我家干嘛
Where is he, Jackie?
他在哪儿, Jackie？
What's going on?
怎么了
Is this the asshole?
就是这个混蛋吗？
What? Who the fuck is this?
什么？这他妈是谁？
Shut the fuck up, Gareth!
他妈闭嘴, Gareth!
Paul, would you leave?
Paul, 出去
So this is the famous Paul.
这就是传说中的Paul啊
You like beating up little girls, do you. You know it's assault, is what it is.
你喜欢打小女孩是吧，你知道这是虐待？
You touch her again. I'll kill you.
你再敢碰她，我杀了你
Is that right, mate?
杀了我，啊？
What do you call this, dickhead?
给我看清楚了，白痴
I always mind my own fucking business.
我只管好我自己的事
Get out of my house, you fucking pricks.
滚出我家，蠢人
Mind your fucking business.
管好你自己的事
You cunt, you fuck off! Is that clear?
你给我滚，清楚了吗？
Still wanna fucking kill me, cunt?
还想杀我吗，蠢人
Gareth, Get the fuck inside.
Gareth, 你他妈进去
Get the fuck inside!
进去！
You think you can come here and do this shit in front of my kids?
你以为你可以闯进我家 在我孩子面前做出这样的事？
Have you seen her fucking bruises? What did you think I was going to do?
你看到她的伤吗？你以为我还能做什么？
She got a lot more than she got. I want you to stay away from her.
她要忍受的还有更多，我要你离她远点
You changed the birth certificate.
你改了出生证明
When were you going to tell her about that?
你准备什么时候告诉她？
Just stay out of our lives, all right?
不要再来烦我们，行吗？
Yeah.
好啊
See you around Paul, you fucking prick.
回头见，Paul，该死的蠢人
Hello?
喂？
Celia?
Celia？
She might have gone to Spain.
她可能去了西班牙
No, no, no, wait.
不不不，等等
My daughter plans on running off to Spain and he sees nothing.
我女儿秘密计划去西班牙，他为她保密
I don't call that irrelevant.
我不认为那很正常
Come on Jackie, it's not like it's the first time she's done something like this.
Jackie, 这也不是她第一次这样做了
Oh great.
太好了
How good, this is good. So you are defending him now?
好啊，你帮着他说话了？
Okay, so when exactly did she say she was running off to Spain?
那好，她具体是什么时候说要去西班牙的？
She didn't. She didn't say. All I knew is she had the ticket.
她没有，没有说出来，我知道她有机票
I thought she was going to leave when school was finished. That's all.
我以为她会等学校放假再走，就是这样
I didn't know what to think.
我不知道该怎么想
Yeah well I know what I think. I think you are out of your mind.
我知道我是怎么想的，我想你疯了
She made me promise not to tell a soul.
她让我保证不告诉任何人
I'm her mother.
我是她的妈妈
OK?
OK？
When exactly did she make this promise Paul?
那她是什么时候这样做的呢？
Was it when you were plying her with alcohol?
是你给她灌酒喝的时候吗？
I wasn't plying her with alcohol. I gave her a glass, Jackie. A child could have drunk it.
我没有灌她，我只是给了她一杯，孩子能喝的
A child did drink it.
孩子是喝了
Oh yeah. And did he think of that when he was punching the shit out of her?
是啊，那他打她的时候她也是那样想的吗？
And the rest.
还有别的
Fuck off. Don't bring me into it.
滚开，别把我扯进去
Sneaking up on her.
偷看她
Pissing in the toilet while she was lying in the bath.
趁她洗澡时故意去厕所
If it took her going half way around the world to get away from you, you fucking a--.
她跑得远远的就是为了躲着你，你他妈的...
You two stay in here.
你们留下
You, get in my office. I want a word alone.
你去我办公室，我和你单独谈
What's he talking about?
他在说什么？
What the fuck is he talking about
他他妈说的是什么？
Nothing!
没什么!
Tell me about the last time you saw her. Everything.
告诉我你最后一次见她的情况，不要隐瞒
We were at the gate. She was carrying the atlas.
我把她送到门口，她拿着地图
She said goodbye and she left.
她告了别，然后离开
No special goodbyes?
没有特殊的告别？
No special goodbyes.
没有特殊的告别
No, she had a couple of books she hadn't got around to read
她有几本书没来得及读
and I told her she could keep them.
我告诉她可以留着
Names of these books?
这些书的名字？
Oh fuck say, what does it matter? I don't know.
这有关吗，我不知道
"Owls Do Cry", by Janet Frame, and another one,
Janet Frame的"Owls Do Cry", 还有一本
Camus, "The Outsider", I think it was.
Camus的"The Outsider", 应该是这本
That's Camus not canoe. C-a-m-u-s.
是Camus，不是canoe. C-a-m-u-s
You smug prick.
自以为是的家伙
Not all of us had to run off to Europe, mate.
不是每个人都想去欧洲的
Travel Diary
旅行日记
passport
护照
"Missing girl, teacher, shared secret den"
"失踪的女孩和老师共处一密室"
I guess you've seen this.
我想你已经看过了
Small town bloody gossip.
小镇的闲言碎语
I don't know what to do about this, Paul.
我不知道怎样处理, Paul.
The board of trustees have called a meeting.
学校高层开了会
You don't deserve this.
我知道你是无辜的
You know it's fine, Pat.
没事的, Pat.
It's time I left anyway. Honestly.
我也该走了，说真的
Hey! Jonathan.
嘿，Jonathan.
Jonathan?
Jonathan？
Jonathan!
Jonathan!
Get in!
上车
Jonathan, get in the car, it's bloody freezing.
Jonathan, 上车，外面太冷了
Come on.
快
Put your seat belt on.
系上安全带
Were you having sex with her?
你和她发生关系了吗？
What?
什么？
You know who.
你知道我说的是谁
Who said that?
谁说的
Kids at school, said you were giving her special coaching in bed.
学校里的孩子，说你在床上给她特殊训练
And you believed them?
你相信他们？
Huh, and you believed
你相信了
How's that camera going? I haven't seen you with it lately.
照相机呢？最近没有看见你用它
As the days went on, more and more people went looking.
日复一日，越来越多的人开始寻找
The people searched far and wide
人们四处寻找
but the ocean had vanished without a trace.
但是大海消失得毫无踪影
The quiet land once bountiful
曾经富饶的大地
had become hard and unyielding.
变得坚硬和贫瘠
Then a shape appeared on the horizon.
地平线上的某物现了形
Through a blaze of hate the people saw
透过恨意的强光，人们看到
what looked like tumbling water rolling towards them.
翻滚的海水向他们袭去
A wave of excitement passed through the town
激烈之浪灌过小镇
as they anxiously watched the ocean return.
当他们焦急地盼着大海回归
But as it grew closer the shape began to alter and mutate.
当它逼近的时候，一切突变
What looked like tumbling water was in fact wild horses.
翻滚的海水其实是大群野马
Everywhere they turned they saw horses drawing closer and closer.
人们眼看马群四处逼近
Their excitement turned to fear.
他们的兴奋转为了恐惧
And their fear became panic,
他们的恐惧成为了恐慌
for it seemed that nothing could stop their advance.
眼见马群的前进无可阻挡
Which as the ocean's disappearance
就如大海的消失
had come without warning.
来得毫无征兆
But then no one,
但是没有人
not even for a moment,
甚至没有一刻时间
had stopped to question why the ocean had left in the first place.
能够质疑为何，大海在最初离开
Mr. Prior?
Prior先生？
I am Detective Inspector Farnon from Wellington CIV.
我是惠灵顿警局的Farno探员
This is Detective Dunleavy.
这是Dunleavy探员
I've a warrant to search these premises.
我有搜查令
And I'll need you to accompany me to the station for questioning.
需要你去警局回答一些问题
I'll need your passport and keys to your car.
我需要你的护照和车钥匙
I believe there's a shed where Celia used to visit you.
我知道Celia常去一个密室和你见面
Right then, let's get you home.
好，我们送你回去
Why did Celia come to your place last Sunday?
上周日Celia为什么去你家？
Did you hear the question?
你听见我的问题了吗？
Yes.
听见了
I understand she visited you regularly.
我知道她定期来见你
What was the nature of the visits?
她来得目的是什么？
We talked about things.
我们谈一些事
What things?
什么事？
Europe.
欧洲
Books.
书
Celia wants to be a writer.
Celia想成为作家
I am not flesh. I am not blood.
我不是肉，我不是血
They can look all they like but they'll never see me.
他们可以尽其所能，但是他们看不见我
If I never hear your love or hold your hand again in this life,
如果这一生我无法再听见你的爱，握你的手
promise me we will touch when I am dead.
向我保证死后我们会再见
It's called 'Poem for a Lonely Friend'.
诗的名字是'Poem for a Lonely Friend'
Would you consider yourself lonely, Paul?
你觉得自己孤独吗, Paul？
Thank you.
谢谢
Would you keep that door closed, please.
请关上门
Why did Celia keep visiting you even though her parents had forbidden it?
为什么Celia坚持来看你，不顾她父母的反对？
Parents?
父母？
Mother.
母亲
I guess she saw something in me.
我想她从我身上看到了一些东西
And what was that?
什么东西？
Well, I'm not Celia.
我不是Celia.
Then perhaps you'd like to tell me what it was you saw in her?
那也许你可以告诉我们，你从她身上看到了什么
I know this is diffi--
我知道这很困难
I remember being her.
我记得成为她的感觉
What did you do this time?
这次你又做了什么？
Come on, leave me alone now .
让我一个人呆着
Go away.
走开
Just fucking go, come on, leave me alone.
走吧你，走吧，让我一个人呆着
I don't need this shit, Celia.Just go.
我不需要你, Celia，走开
What?
怎么了
Did mom say something to you?
我妈跟你说了什么了吗？
Your mum threatened to ring the school, yeah.
你妈威胁说要告诉学校
Okay?
可以了吗？
No, it's not ok.
不，不可以
God, she's so fucking presumptuous.
她太他妈不讲理了
Who the fuck cares what she thinks?
谁他妈在乎她怎么想的
She's got a fucking boyfriend he wears boat shoes.
她那个讨厌的男友穿着像船那么大的鞋子
He brought her a pair now they're both wearing them.
他也给她买了一双，现在他们一个鼻子出气了
You never see a fucking boat around here.
在这儿他妈一只船都看不到
I just came to tell you that I entered the contest .
我来是要告诉你我参加那个比赛了
Well that's great, now get going.
那很好，加油吧
It's not illegal that we're friends or something, Paul.
我们不是不可以做朋友, Paul.
It was you who said that we shouldn't care what other people think of us.
是你说的，我们不该在意别人的想法
Or were you just saying that?
难道你只是说说而已
You know how you and mom used to go out and now it me and you that are friends.
你和我妈曾是恋人，现在我们是朋友
I feel like I've known you my whole life.
我感觉我这一生都有你这个朋友
Yeah well, it's a small world.
是啊，这个世界很小
It isn't a small world.
世界并不小
Were you guys in love?
你们当时相爱吗？
There must've been something going on if you tattooed each others feet.
你们把对方的名字纹在脚趾上，一定不只是儿戏
It's a little hard to imagine what you saw in her.
有些难以想象你在她身上看到了什么
Well, you're not the first person to feel that way about their parents.
你不是唯一一个对父母抱有这样想法的人
Anyway, it's a long time ago.
算了，都是很久以前的事了
I know it wasn't planned.
也许就是那样
Mom was only 16.
妈那时才16岁
You'd tell me if you knew anything, eh?
如果你心里有什么事，会告诉我的吧
Is that a promise?
保证吗？
Oh stuff it.
行了
Let's get wet. Come on.
淋雨去吧，走
Mazzy Star "Take Everything"
Mazzy Star "Take Everything"
Oh, geez!
天啊
Andrew, Jonathan?
Andrew, Jonathan？
We were on our way home from church and thought we'd stop in for a cuppa.
我们从教堂回家，想进来坐坐
Fuck.
该死
It's freezing!
太冷了
Have you see this new thing that they're building?
你看到他们在造的新东西吗？
It looks like a giant barn.
像一个大粮仓
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
我去一下洗手间
I'll put the kettle on.
我去烧水
Family and friends of Celia Steimer
Celia Steimer的家人和朋友
are doing everything possible to help police find her.
正协助警方寻找她
More than 50 volunteers are now scouring waterways and bushlands
超过50名志愿者从水路寻找失踪女孩
in the Marshall road forest.
在马歇尔路森林
The 16-year-old Rapari Junction HS student
这位16岁的中学生
has been missing now for more than a week.
失踪超过一周
Detective Robin Farland says
Robin Farland探员表示
they have to consider every option.
他们不得不考虑种种可能性
She acknowledged a local man is helping them with their inquiries
她还表示一位当地市民正在帮助他们的调查
and the police will be visiting every house in the area.
警方将会拜访当地的每一家人
He'll be fine.
他不会有事的
Let them handle it.
让他们处理吧
Please just use an ashtray.
请用烟灰缸
Okay.
好的
Listen, I spoke to the lawyer in Alexandria
听着，我跟Alexandria的律师谈过了
and he reckons he's handled this sort of thing before.
他过去处理过这样的事
He wants you to give him a call first thing in the morning.
他想让你明天一早给他打个电话
Hey, what sexual position creates the ugliest offspring?
嘿，你说怎样的性交姿势能生出最丑的孩子
What sexual position creates--
怎样的性交姿势能生出...
I don't know, Paul.
我不知道, Paul
Ask your mother.
问问你妈
Can you imagine if she saw us now?
你能想象如果她现在看到我们会怎样吗？
Can you imagine that? What do you think she'd say?
你能想象吗，你觉得她会说什么？
Two brothers having a drink and a chat.
兄弟俩边喝边谈
What do you think? She'd be proud, or what?
你说呢？她会骄傲吗？
Why are you doing this?
你在说什么？
Doing what?
什么什么？
You know exactly what.
你知道什么
Why can't you just talk to me?
你为什么就不能跟我说
Fuck you.
去你的
What the fuck are you looking at? Never seen two brothers talking before?
你他妈在看什么？没见过兄弟俩说话？
You want to talk, let's talk.
你想谈，那我们谈
Forget the fact you come in here blind drunk
别忘了你醉醺醺闯到这里
and interrupt a meeting but then you just bring up mom like that?
打断我的会议，忽然就提起妈来了
I mean how dare you? I realize you are in a spot of bother, Paul,
我说你怎么敢？我知道你现在不太好, Paul,
but that doesn't give you the right to behave like this.
不过那并不代表你可以这样做
The truth? You were never there for mom.
想知道真相？你从来就没有关心过母亲
When she was sick, where the hell were you?
她病的时候，你在哪里
Brilliant. So you do have an opinion. OK Andrew.
太好了，现在你有意见了，好啊，Andrew
What the fuck is that supposed to mean? I couldn't get near her.
你他妈什么意思？我都不能接近她
Blame it all on me. I had to be you. Did you know that?
都怪我好了，我还得扮演你的角色，忘了吗？
You made fucking sure of it.
你他妈想想清楚
The happy little fucking threesome: Andy, mom and God.
快乐的三人世界：Andy，妈妈，还有上帝
No one else invited.
没有别人打扰
You abandoned her.
你抛弃了她
You abandoned her, Paul. And you never took one single step towards--
你抛弃了她, Paul. 你从来没有迈出一步...
at least for all his faults, he let me in. He let me in.
他做错过事，可是他接受了我
You were late for his funeral, remember? And you're gonna stand here defending for him.
你连他的葬礼都没有赶到 现却在站在这里为他说话
Listen to me Paul, you listen, listen to me.
听我说，Paul，你听我说
You know sometimes I look at you
有时候我看着你
and all I see is him.
看到的都是他
Just him.
只是他
I find that quite disheartening.
那令我沮丧
Yeah well, at least I didn't marry my fucking mother.
至少我没他妈娶我的妈
Has she always been like that or just when she met you?
她一直是那样的，还是只有见到你时那样？
Go to hell, Paul.
去死吧，Paul
Police confirm blood traces belong to missing girl.
警察表示血迹属于失踪的女孩
Just open it!
打开
Celia, give me the fucking letter carta.
Celia, 把信封给我
It doesn't matter.
没用的
Open it. Will you just open it?
打开，打开好吗？
No! Don't open it.
不，别打开
Open it!
打开
I don't want to.
我不想
No?
不想？
No.
不想
Wonder who came in first?
谁得了第一呢？
Amid the 2000 or so entries
在两千多名参赛者中
we were delighted with Ms Steimers' story.
我们很欣赏Steimers小姐的文章
This work shows an emerging remarkable talent for someone so young.
这篇作品显示了一个年轻人的才华
It catches a sense of beauty, mystery and loss
它捕获了一种美感，神秘感，和迷失感
without ever losing sight of what might be.
同时并未丧失清醒
You wonder who came first?
谁第一...
I'll tell you who came first.
我来告诉你
Someone three times your age, probably, someone who bloody well deserved to come first.
很可能是年长你三倍的某个人 值得拿第一的某个人
Thank you for making it special for me.
谢谢你让我感觉如此特别
The den and everything.
小屋，还有其他一切
I need a cigarette to cope with this sort of scenery.
我要抽根烟，来享受这美景
In the car.I'll be back in a tic.
我去车里拿烟，马上回来
Can you leave me your jacket?
能把外套给我吗？
Are you gonna be home tonight? I need you to baby sit Sam.
你今晚出门吗，我想要你看着Sam
Celia, I asked you a question.
Celia, 我在跟你说话
Fuck!
该死
Is he my father?
他是我爸爸吗？
I wish it were that simple.
如果是那样简单就好了
Hey, you!
嘿
What's up?
怎么了
Did you know?
你知道吗？
Answer me! Did you know?
回答我，你知道吗？
Oh, Celia...
哦, Celia...
I know what you did when you took the photo of that girl.
我知道你拍下那个女孩的照片之后做了什么
You walked away and left her.
你走开了，你离开了她
That's why you withdrew the entry so you wouldn't even have to deal with her.
那就是你退出提名的原因，这样你不用再为此困扰了
You don't know--
你不知道...
don't!
别说了
Was she just another photo?
她只是另一张照片吗？
Just another picture of this fucking war puzzle that you try to figure out?
只是你为了解开该死的战争迷题 拍下的一张照片吗？
Was she just like me?
她是另一个我吗？
Was she just someone you could pick up and throw away and forget about?
她只是你随便扔掉和忘记的人吗？
How do you live with yourself?
你怎么可以这样
Andrew! Penny!
Andrew! Penny!
Are you there?
你们在吗？
Will you just open the door?
开开门
I just need somewhere to stay.
我只是想要个落脚之处
Come on Penny, I know you're in there.
Penny, 我知道你在里面
You know Jonathan, all that stuff in the papers,
Jonathan, 报纸上写的那些
that's all just speculation.
只是猜测
All right? It's rubbish.
都是垃圾
They have no proof.
他们没有证据
I'm still your uncle.
我还是你的叔叔
No you're not.
不，你不是
We both think you're fucking stupid.
我们都觉得你他妈太笨了
What did you say?
你说什么？
Leave me alone!
放开我
I hope they kill you.
我希望他们杀了你
I hope they--
我希望他们...
It's okay!
没事的
It's alright. I know you like her.
没事的，我知道你喜欢她
Listen, you have to tell me what you meant by "both of you".
听着，你得告诉我“你们”是什么意思
Look at me.
看着我
What did you mean by "both of us think you're stupid"?
“我们都觉得你很笨”是什么意思？
Tell me what you meant by "both of us".
告诉我“我们”是谁
I'm not gonna hurt you. I promise I won't hurt you.
我不会伤害你，我保证不会伤害你
What is it, Jonathan?
什么意思, Jonathan？
I was looking for my camera.
我在找我的相机
I thought he was hiding it to protect you.
我以为他藏起来是为了保护你
Where is he?
他在哪儿
In Christchurch till tomorrow.
明天以前都在教堂
Paul!
Paul!
Paul, are you there?
Paul, 你在吗？
RIVER
河边
I just heard from the lawyer.
我刚听律师说
What do you mean you don't want to sell?
你不想卖是什么意思？
You can't. I'm up to my eyeballs--
你不行，我手头正紧...
What the hell did you do that for?
你他妈在干嘛
Get up!
起来
What were you going to do? Plant it at my place like the atlas?
你想做什么？把它藏到我家，跟那张地图一样？
This is really unnecessary
你不需要这样的
Okay! Okay!
好吧，好吧
There was a time I wondered why you up and left.
我曾经想过你为什么就那样走了
You knew what he was up to, didn't you?
你知道他要做什么的，不是吗？
At least look at me and tell me
至少看着我说
before you pull the trigger.
在你扣动扳机之前
You know the really sad part?
你知道最可悲的是什么吗？
I didn't even find out until I read the will.
直到看了遗嘱，我才知道
That's how far back I was.
我是那样无知
But then how was I to know, Paul?
那时我怎么会懂, Paul
I was only a kid, a 15-year-old kid.
我还是个孩子，十五岁的孩子
You killed me when you walked away and left me with that evil piece of scum.
你走得一干二净，把我留给了那个卑贱的人
You think you even get a second fucking chance?
你以为你他妈会有第二次机会？
You knew, you bastard!
你知道的，畜牲
And you had the gall to come back here and bring that thing into our house.
你还有胆回来，把那野种带到我们家
My mother's house!
我妈妈的家！
And god knows what you're doing with her, but then like father like son.
天知道你和她干了些什么，有其父必有其子
Andrew, you don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
Andrew, 你他妈不知道你在说什么
He was screwing that teenage whore of yours.
他干了你那年轻的婊子
No!
不!
- He was. You knew it. - No!
- 他干了，你知道的 - 不!
And you walked.
你走开了
Andrew no! It's got nothing to fucking do with you!
Andrew，别说了，这他妈与你无关
You saw it with your own eyes!
你亲眼看见了
You knew and you walked and you never looked back.
你知道了，走开了，再没有回头
What did you do to her?
你对她做了什么？
Our mother died the moment that bastard was conceived.
那个野种被怀上的时候，正是妈死的时候
Just tell me.
告诉我
Go ahead and cry.
哭吧
It's about time you cried for our mother.
你该为我们的母亲痛哭了
I'll kill you. I fucking swear I'll kill you.
我要杀了你，我他妈发誓要杀了你
I told her everything.
我把什么都告诉她了
Everything!
全部
Someone had to set the record straight.
必须要有人做出正确的事情
I had a right to that money, Paul.
我有权拿到那笔钱, Paul.
That money was mine if nothing else, at least that.
那笔钱应该是我的，至少是那样
And I should give her a third at 18 along with a nice little letter.
可是从她18岁开始，我要给她三分之一财产， 还要写一封漂亮的信
Rather convenient, eh? Nice and smooth.
还是干掉她方便，不是吗？
She wanted proof.
她想要证据
She asked to see the will.
她要看遗嘱
Wait here.
等在这里
Mom was there.
妈妈在那里
She...
她...
What?
什么？
What are you doing in here?
你在这里干嘛
I was just looking.
随便看看
Who are you
你是谁
He brought me here.
他带我来的
I know what you are.
我知道你是什么？
You have no right to be in my house.
你没权利来我家
I want you to stay away from my family. Is that clear? Stay away.
离我家人远点，清楚吗，走开
So he told you about me.
那么他告诉你我的事了
Haven't you told her?
你跟她说了没
I told you to wait outside.
我让你在外面等的
Is it true, Andrew?
这是真的吗, Andrew？
You people.
你们这些人
Get out!
出去
She smiled, Paul.
她笑了, Paul.
Simple misunderstanding.
简单的误会
What's done is done.
该做的完成了
For what it's worth mum wants it this way.
无论如何这是妈妈想要的结果
Uncle Paul?
Paul叔叔？
Jonathan...
Jonathan...
Can you come over?
你能过来吗？
I rang the police.
我叫了警察
Am I in trouble?
我有麻烦了吗？
No, you're not.
不，不会的
Mazzy Star "Into Dust"
Mazzy Star "Into Dust"
Paul, wait!
Paul, 等等
Paul, come back home!
Paul, 回家来
Paul, don't leave!
Paul, 别走
Paul!
Paul!
The people had no choice
人们别无选择
but to trust that the horses would lead them to their ocean.
只能选择相信，马群将会带领他们去向大海
Without reins or saddles
没有缰绳和马鞍
they rode the horses across the barren land.
他们骑马越过贫瘠的大地
But the ocean had disappeared for good.
但是大海还是永远消失了
And the people, together and alone had no choice
孤独的人们别无选择
but to face each other in their loss.
在迷失中面对彼此
They made a home for themselves in a new environment.
他们在新的地方建立了家园
Although one that had changed forever.
一切改变
They learnt to live in the space that the ocean had left.
他们学会了面对没有大海的生活
One day the tide went away
“潮退的那一天”
Although it lingered in their dreams.
逗留在他们的梦中
Celia!
Celia!
Your e-mail said it was urgent.
你在信上说有急事
Yeah,
是啊
I just wanted to see you.
只是想见见你
I've just been reading your story.
我在读你的文章
So, you want to come in?Have a cup of tea?
进来吗？喝杯茶？
I'll make you a macchito.
我给你做杯macchito
I wanted to give you this.
我想给你这个
It's a bit out of date.
有点过时了
I don't think the world has changed that much in 25 years.
不过我想25年之内世界没有太大的改变
Have a look inside.
看看里面
What's this?
这是什么？
What do you think it is?
你说是什么
It's open. So you can use it anytime you like.
这是不定期的，随时用都可以
You can leave after school's finished.
学校放假之后你可以去
Hey, Celia, this is not some pathetic attempt
Celia, 这不是什么可悲的弥补
to make everything all right.
想让一切好起来
It's just--
它只是...
the ticket is just a gift.
机票只是我的礼物 02:00:25,500 --